The cellular link is a basic communication between two entities.
It's an asynchronous transmission using only two lines: TX for transmitting data and XR for receiving
data.
In this cellular communication we can use a few parameters and these parameters must be the same on
the transmitter and on the receiver.
We can't get these parameters, so we need to follow the documentation of the system we want to connect
to.
In this example, I will try to connect to my LoRaWAN device.
Usually when the device is deployed in the field, the logs are disabled.
So of course we don't need a cellular link, but in our case we've programmed this specific device with
locks activated to show many information. That will allow us to understand its state, what it sends
and what it receives.
So to connect to this device, I use MobaXTerm.
If you don't have it, then you can use the putty software, which is one of the most famous cellular
link terminal.
That's actually the one embedded in MobaXTerm.
So I open a new session and select "serial".
I first need to select the port COM number.
I want to connect.
Your device should appear in the list.
Or at least we should see the COM port number where the remote device is connected.
Then we select the board
Right.
In my case, it's 115 200 per second.
Most of the time this is the only configuration we need to do.
But in case our device has some specific transmission parameters, we can change them in the Advanced
Settings tab.
We'll be able to specify the number of bit, the number of stop bit, and if there is a parity error
bit at the end of the frame.
In our case, we don't change anything and we click okay.
There we go.
We have the logs of our device.
One more thing.
The most commands speed transmission use is indeed 115 200 feet per second.
It might be a good idea to have it preconfigured with this default value when you open a new serial
session.
For that you need to go to Settings, Edit Session Preset, select your favorite speed.
In our case, it's this one and save. The next time you open a serial session, your favorite board
rate and other parameters will be applied.